Okay, we are live. Good.
Okay, welcome. Sorry for about the uh
technical difficulties um as the link
got cut off and we had to create a new
one. But just wanted to welcome you uh
for those who are watching and attending
for the first time. My name is Pastor
Lwami Richardson and I am the young
adult pastor here at Living Mana Church
and welcome to the safe place. Uh this
is our Thursday night program that we
have dedicated uh specifically to our
young adults, millennials, Jenzers who
is looking to uh learn more about
practical Christianity and relevant
topics that are dear to our experiences
and to our lives. And so we are in the
middle of a series entitled the
prescription. And this series is uh
highlighting the importance of what it
means to have a real tangible Christian
experience uh in our everyday uh walk of
life. And so I just want to encourage
those who have not uh already joined the
mighty networks uh there will be a link
provided and you can join uh the mighty
networks. And and please we also want to
encourage you to go and share this bread
and this uh word uh to those who you
know would be uh be blessed by the
messages that we have uh presented and
who will be blessed by the message
today. So just a quick recap before we
dive into our study and I know our time
is limited um but we might have to
expand this series as I I didn't re or
not the series but this topic in
particular did not realize it was this
long um of of emphasis but or this this
part of the presentation I didn't
realize it was this extensive but uh I
just want to kind of do a quick recap
for those who are watching uh we
discussed in step number one uh the the
the the thing that we need to be doing
the first thing in the morning. And many
of us grab our phones, we turn on the
TV, we try to catch up on the latest
news, whether it be the sports
highlights or our stocks, whatever it
may be. But we have established that the
example that Jesus left us is the first
thing that he did when he woke up in the
morning was to commune with his father
is to consecrate his plans and take the
plans of his father and demonstrate that
in his everyday life. And then we see in
step number two that we must consent to
God's plan for our lives. And we must do
this on a daytoday basis. And the reason
why God allows us and permits us to go
through various experiences is to give a
word in due season to those who may be
going through dark times and difficult
moments. And so the the reality of the
Christian experience isn't wasted. It is
meant to be an encouragement to others
that we come in contact with. And there
was a challenge that was presented. And
you can go back to watch that
presentation. But the last week and this
week and possibly next week, we are
covering step number three. We are uh uh
we are in the step of asking. But it's
not just requesting God about our
finances or a spouse or material things.
But in reality, we are asking God for
the Holy Spirit to dwell in us to live
out the very principles that Jesus lived
while he was here on earth. So, it's not
just waking up in the morning, having my
devotion and praying, but I'm actually
asking the Holy Spirit to dwell within
my heart and in my life that he the Holy
Spirit will guide me in the decision-
making that I make throughout the day.
And as I'm asking for the Holy Spirit,
his plan, and I'm consenting to his will
be un uh uh revealed day by day. So,
we're going to dive right in. We're
going to start with a word of prayer. Um
and then we're going to get into our
topic. We have about 30 minutes, so I'll
try to cover as much as possible. And if
there's any questions, please leave them
in the in the chat or you can leave
those uh questions in our Mighty Network
um uh app um at our Mighty Networks
group. But let us bow our heads for a
word of prayer and invite the Holy
Spirit to be with us and guide us into
our topic tonight. Let us pray. Father,
we just want to thank you so much for
your love and your grace. And um as we
was listening to the song that you have
not given us up on us yet, it has been
an encouragement for me this week to
know that as I'm transforming and
transitioning into the person that
you've called me to be that there are
scars, there are wounds. There are
things that uh I am unfamiliar with, but
thank God for your grace. Thank God for
your patience. Thank God for your love
for we can become new creations and new
creatures um because you have given us
the power and the ability to do so. So I
just ask that Moami Richardson may not
be heard or seen, but that everybody who
may be watching now in the future may be
drawn to the beautiful image that is
your son Jesus Christ. For we ask this
in Jesus precious and holy name. Amen.
And amen. So we're going to be going
through a couple of quotations here to
piggyback on what we was been discussing
discussing as we are talking about the
topic of asking for the Holy Spirit.
Thoughts of the mount of blessings page
101 states that Christ has given no
promise of help in bearing today the
burdens of tomorrow. So often the reason
why majority of of the world suffer with
anxiety is because we are so stressed
out about the things in the future. In
just the last few days, we have seen the
economic turnover uh uh turmoil that
we've been experiencing from the stock
markets to tariffs and all of these
things, right? People's 401ks being
wiped out and we are so stressed about
what's going to happen tomorrow. But
Christ has not given us any promise
about the burdens we need to carry
tomorrow. He says in 2 Corinthians 12
and:9 that my grace is sufficient for
thee. So the grace that God imparts for
us is meant for us to find peace in the
chaos that you and I experience. But
like mana given in the wilderness when
we look at the example given in the
story of Israel as they was in the
wilderness and God gave them mana in
order for them to survive as he was
preparing them to enter into the
promised land. The grace that he gives
us is given to us daily. Just like God
gave the people of Israel mana daily. He
never said to uh hoard up all of the
mana for today so you could prepare for
tomorrow. He only did that on Friday
because he understood the importance of
the Sabbath and resting. Right? And we
need to start developing the the faith
in knowing that God will provide the
essential mana, the essential grace
needed for us to be overcomers today. So
just like Israel in their pilgrim life,
we may find morning by morning the bread
of heaven for the day's supply. This is
why it is so important for us to uh be
intentional in our devotional life in
the morning to not just make these uh
quick microwave prayers and these quick
two-minute devotions but really taking
the time and carving out time in the
morning early in the morning as Jesus
led the example to really commune with
him to really seek out his will for that
day to seek the word that he would want
us to read and to uh uh understand what
it is that we need for that day. I
shared this example last week where I've
been kind of slipping on my my early
morning devotions, right? And I asked
God, "What is it that you would like me
for me to study?" And he reverted back
to pick up the study on the life of
David. And that that mana that I was
receiving for that day, what the spirit
revealed to me, I wanted to share on
Facebook. And I shared last week that
that Facebook post from my morning
devotion was actually an encouragement
and a blessing to others who was going
through that same experience. And so
this is why we need to be in tune with
the Holy Spirit. This is why we need to
have daily morning communion with God
and seeking for that fresh this uh
supply of his
grace. Um it continues to say that one
day alone is ours and during this day we
are to live for God. So in other words,
we're not worrying about what happened
yesterday. Yesterday is forgotten. We
have asked God to forgive us, to cleanse
us from the things that we have already
committed. He has given us a new day.
And we're not promised tomorrow. So the
day that we have today alone is ours.
And in this day that God has given us,
we should live for him. Right? For this
one day, she states, we are to place in
the hand of God in solemn service all of
our purposes and plans. So again, God
may give you a trajectory of what your
life uh is going to look like, the
passions, the the the the uh the the
things that are important to you, the
things that make you come alive. God
wants to honor those things, but he
wants it to not be perverted by our own
self-interest and our own uh
selfishness, right? He wants those plans
that he has placed in your heart to
fulfill. All those purposes and plans
need to be surrendered to God every
single day. So in this grand theme of
the purpose that God has given me in my
life to impact young people and to work
those in the inner city community that
is the trajectory of the life that God
will want me to live. So any decision or
any petition or anything that I am um
laboring for is to fulfill God's
ultimate plan and purpose for my life.
But as I wake up today, how does today
uh will allow me to continue to live out
the godforgiving gifts and purpose that
he has laid out for me to live? So the
Bible tells us that we should cast all
our care upon him. Why? Because he cares
for us. The reason why he cares for us
is because he knows the thought that I
thinks toward you, says the Lord.
Thoughts of peace, not of evil, to give
you expected end. In return, the rest
shall be saved. In quietness and
confidence shall be your strength. So
God says, listen, tomorrow's not
promised. Yesterday is forgotten. Let us
focus on the present. Right? Let us
focus on today. Let us ask God for all
of his purpose and his plans to be
revealed for us for this day. And to
know that the thoughts that God has for
me at the end of it all, it's thoughts
of peace, not evil for and ultimately
all the experiences that we come through
is for an expected end. It is to reveal
God's love and what he has done in our
lives to be a revelation of that love to
those we come
across. So that's thoughts of the mounts
of blessed page 101. But it concludes by
saying, "If you seek the will of the
Lord and be converted every day, if you
will of your own spiritual choice choose
be uh choose be free and joyous in God,
if with gladsome consent of heart to
gracious call, you come wearing the yoke
of Christ, the yoke of obedience and
service, all your murmurings will still
be still. All of your difficulties will
be removed and all perplexing problems
that now confront you will be solved.
Now, this is a mouthful, but really
unpacked what we just read. Listen to
this. If you seek the Lord and be
converted every day, so meaning just
because you was converted yesterday
don't mean that you're converted today,
right? Like we believe that
sanctification is a work of a lifetime.
We are constantly learning things about
ourselves. There are new thoughts, new
experiences. And as we wrestle through
these things, they may be moments where
we fall and we slip, right? Because the
experiences from yesterday may not be
the experiences today. So God is calling
us to say, I need you to convert your
ways of thinking and the way that you
handle difficult situations and and
surrender those to me so that I can help
you convert yourself into not
approaching uh situations and problems
the way that you always had. Right? But
notice what she says. If you will of
your own spiritual choice be free and
joyous in God. So we can either be
miserable in our experience with God or
we can be joyous in the experience with
God. We can either experience freedom or
we can experience prison. And what I'm
seeing in many Christians uh lives and
what I when I speak is that there's not
a lot of joy, there's not a lot of
freedom, but yet they say that they
serve the God. So we have a choice to be
free and choice in God. I am free to
choose what I want to choose because my
choices are no longer mine. My choices
are aligned with God's ideal and his
plan for me. Does that make sense? So if
with glad some gladsome consent of
heart. So when God says, "I need you to
surrender this thing." When God says, "I
need you to speak to this person." When
God says, "I need you to go apply for
this position," or, "I need you to make
with with somebody from your past,"
whatever it is that God is asking of
you, because we've already established
that not only are we uh requesting our
our petitions before the Lord, but we
are consenting to the plan that he has
for us. So when he gives me my orders
for the day, I am consenting with a
happy heart, right? To his gracious
call, you come wearing the yoke of
Christ. I am no longer accepting my
burden. I'm taking on the burden of God
of of Jesus because his burden is light,
right? His yoke is easy. My yoke and my
burdens are heavy to bear. Hence the
reason why God needs to take them and
replace it with his. Are you following
me so far? And not only that, they said
the yoke of obedience. Ooh, that word,
it is so ugly in so many Christian
circles. But that word obedience is not
an ugly word when we're already in a
relationship with God that is joyous and
we're consenting and we are free in him.
Right? So the yoke of obedience. So I'm
taking the burden of trying to figure
out problems on my own. I am now
relieving that burden to God, taking on
his yoke, allowing him to uh help me uh
give me the ability to obey his precepts
and his plans for me for that day and
ultimately serve those he is asking me
to serve. So once I do this,
saints, notice what takes place. My
murmurings stop. My difficulties are
removed. And all perplexing problems now
confront me are solved. The reason why
saints, many of us are still dealing
with difficult situations, the reason
why we are still dealing with perplexing
problems, the reason why our situations
are not fully solved is because number
one, we have not sought God. Number two,
we're not converted into the plan that
he has for us. Number three, we don't
even have the we're not freely choosing
and being joyful in the experience with
God. That we are consenting with happy
hearts, knowing that his plans that he
has for me are not ill will plans. They
are plans for me to prosper. That his
plans in my life are meant to give me
peace. We already established that in
the verse before what we read in
Jeremiah 29 and 11 and Isaiah chapter 30
and:e1 15 that the thoughts that he has
towards me is thoughts of peace not of
evil and to ultimately have an expected
end and in return right he gives me rest
in knowing that the plan that he has for
me it will come to fluition.
So are you perplexed with problems? Are
you murmuring right throughout this
experience? If you find yourself in that
situation, then you need to reset and
collaborate and say, "Okay, God, am I
entering into the joy of your
experience? Am I really free in you? Am
I really seeking your plan in my life
for today? Am I really converted or am I
just saying things and not really by
heart following the things that you're
asking me to follow?" That's what I
wanted to leave with you. But let's
continue. So, messages to young people,
page 71. Many poor souls are groping in
darkness, looking for the feelings which
others say they have had in their
experience. They overlook the fact that
the believer in Christ must work out his
own salvation with fear and trembling.
The convicted sinner has something to
do. He must repent and to show true
faith. Meaning, God, I've been doing it
on my own for so long. I thought that my
thoughts and my ways were better than
your thoughts and your ways that you
have for me. So I need to turn away from
my way of thinking, from my way of
resolving problems and submit to your
plan and have true faith that your word
that you have proclaimed will not go
back to you void. So in other words, in
a very practical sense, if God says that
your assurance is secure in me, then I'm
not questioning or doubting God's word
when I falter and fall. Why? because he
is working out his own purpose in my
life. And as long as I have consented,
as long as I believe that he is working
out his goodwill in my life, then I am
free to choose what he's asking me to
choose, I am being joyous in my
experience with him. And this is the
reason why we play the song, Lord, don't
give up on me yet. Because there are new
experiences, new challenges, new
perplexities that I deal with that I
have not figured out because I have not
trusted you with this area of my life.
And God understands that. Why? Because
we're in a relationship with
God. So it continues to
say, so as many poor souls, when Jesus
speaks of a new heart, listen to this,
he means the mind, right? So the heart
and the mind are interconnecting. So So
we have to understand that we're not
basing things off emotions, but we are
intellectually coming and agreeing with
what God has for us. Right? So when
Jesus speaks of a new heart, he means
the mind. He means the life and he means
the entire whole be being. So it's not
just he's not just wanting the mind. He
wants the mind, body and the soul. He
wants every aspect of our being to be
surrendered to his plan for our lives.
Right? So to have a change of heart,
notice this, it is to withdraw the
affections from the world. It is the
things that I have uh uh put faith in,
the things that I have put my trust in,
the things that I have put my joy in and
my happiness in those affections does
not need to go to things that are tempor
temporary but in in but but in instead I
need to focus on things that are
internal that's going to give me
fulfillment and longevity of happiness.
Okay. So to have a change of heart, to
have a change of life, right? To to to
to have a new mind and to ha and be a
new creation in God, I need to remove my
affection for the world. And then I need
to focus on God's plan for my life,
right? And then to have a new heart is
to have a new mind, new purpose, and new
motives. Meaning, I am no longer living
for myself, but I am now being used as a
vessel that God may use me to fill out
his plan for this day. Cuz you could
choose to serve God today and choose not
to follow him tomorrow. Are you
following me? Because tomorrow's not
promised. I can't sit here and wallow
about things that I've done yesterday
because yesterday is gone. So, I need to
have a new mind, a new purpose, and a
new motive today. Right? So notice this.
She asked a question. So what is the
sign of a new heart? It's a very simple
question. She gives the answer. A
changed
life. So to have a new heart is to have
a new mind. It is ultimately to have a
new life. The things that I used to do,
I no longer do. The way the the thought
patterns that I used to possess, I no
longer possess those thought patterns.
those triggers that I used to respond
to, I no longer those triggers still may
be there, but I now respond in a more uh
godly way. I understand to how to
analyze and to process what I'm
experiencing and internalize it and not
project it onto the people that has
quote unquote triggered me. Are you
following what I'm saying? So, what does
it mean to have a sign of a new heart?
It is mean a changed life. There is a
daily hourly dying to selfishness and
pride. So this is why the enemy
understands that we if we're not
constantly connected with
God that he will use any opportunity,
any leverage that he can use, he would
take it to he would utilize it to his
advantage. There has to be a daily
consenting of the plan. So I wake up in
the morning, God reveals to me what I'm
what I'mma study. He's revealing to me
the things that I need to confess to
him. The the the requests I'm
petitioning to him. God is revealing
things. Okay, you're going to go to
work. Uh, but after work, you need to
go, you know, here. And in while at the
grocery store, God may see I may see
somebody at the grocery store. God may
whisper a word. You need to say this.
And I say it, right? And I'm complying.
But then as soon as I did that part of
the day, let's say I get into the car
and now I see a homeless person needing
money. And God is saying, you know what?
I need you to uh spare a couple of
change, a couple of dollars for this
person to buy a hotel room for them to
stay the night, whatever it may be.
Right? I'm just giving an example. And
immediately at that point, I'm just
like, "No, I'm good. I got to go home."
At that moment, saints, we don't have a
new heart. At that hour, we didn't die
to our selfishness and pride. We did our
own decision and choice. So, it's not
just a daily thing. Okay, I surrender
myself to God in the morning. Because by
the time you come home at evening, you
can be a whole completely different
person. I know I have, right? If we're
being really truly honest with God, we
have woke up in the morning had a bomb
devotion. We are singing praises to God.
We we went we did all of the right
things and then all of a sudden by the
afternoon you're wiped. You don't want
to talk nobody. You don't want to hear
nothing from nobody, right? You are
ticked off because your boss did X, Y,
and Z. There has to be a daily, hourly
dying to selfishness and pride. Not my
will, but your will be done throughout
the day. It is unsafe, notice this, to
trust to feelings or
impressions. These are unreliable
guides. God's law is the only correct
standard of holiness. It is by this law
that character is to be judged. True
sanctification will be evidenced by the
consensious regard for all the
commandments of God by a careful
improvement of every talent. And I need
to expand on this as a comma. So, let me
finish it. right? By a circum
circumspect conversion by revealing in
every act the meekness of Christ. So at
the end of the day that God has set up a
law that you and I must comply to. We
can't keep it on our own strength. So he
says by law have I written in your heart
that I might not sin against thee. So
I'm asking God place your heart of love
into my life. We look at the ten
commandments and we can quote uh h
Exodus chapter 20 and and and lay out
all of the ten commandments. But if
we're not having a heart experience with
it, they're just a bunch of legal rules
that you and I must comply to. But that
law ultimately converts us because
Christ was able to do something that you
and I weren't able to do. And what is
that? He was able to keep that law in
perfect harmony with his father, in
perfect love. He showed the perfect
balance of what it meant to love God
with all your heart, mind, and soul. And
he translated that to the people he came
across and came in contact with on a
daily basis. So in every action, I am
demonstrating the meekness of Christ. So
I need to improve on every talent.
Meaning if it's speaking, God says you
need to improve on your talking. If it's
managing your finances, you need to be a
master and improve on that talent.
Whatever the gift that God has given
you, we must constantly be improving so
that way we can demonstrate
uh the true conversion of every act that
we get uh that that we demonstrate and
to reveal the meekness of Christ. So
messages to young people says that let
us make God's holy word our study
bringing its holy principle into our
lives. Let us walk before God in
meekness and humility. notice daily
correcting our faults. I I want to stop
right here for for a second. Let me
finish the quotation and I want to harp
on that point. Let us not be by selfish
pride separate the soul from God.
Cherish not a feeling of lofty supremacy
thinking yourselves better than
others. Oh man, this is the safe place
right so I can speak. I've noticed that
people have bought in and have given
into their preconceived biases and
notions of whatever it may be and won't
allow anyone to change their
perspective. And in this season of my
life, because I can only speak for Lammy
Richardson. In this season of my life,
God has told me to be quick to listen,
slow to talk, follow the principle of
Isaiah, and come and let us reason
together. And one of the ways that we
come reasoning together is to find
points of truth, find points that we
agree upon and then you know what I'm
saying, try to show them in the
direction and where God is leading them
or God has led you to the truth and
helping them to lead into that truth.
And and and we just recent I just
recently did a workshop at a church and
we was doing this exercise of how to be
soul winners and how to witness to
people. And God bless these people's
heart. They have a genuine heart to
really be soul winners for God. But they
have been entrenched for the last 20,
30, 40 years of how to defend the truth
rather than living the
truth.
Yeah, I'm not in a congregation because
I would have heard of mercy. Come on,
pastor.
We we have for so many years defended
the truth and never took the time to
live the truth. So when we talked about
the topic of the Sabbath, for
example, it was amazing to see the
questions that were presented which
almost came off as condescending
questions. Well, are you a believer of
the Bible? Are you a true disciple of
God? And it's like, man, as somebody who
never never ever ever heard the Sabbath
truth, those questions can really be a
turnoff. And one of the things that I
mentioned in this workshop, and I hope
that you guys will listen to what I'm
saying,
is rather than defending the truth, why
don't I allow people to enter into that
experience of the
truth? No, I don't think you understand.
So instead of telling people that the
Sabbath is a seventh day, which is
factually correct, why don't we invite
people into how we Shabbat and how we
rest in God? The problem is that many of
us, if we talk people into our Sabbath
experience, they will find no joy in it.
They will find restriction in the way
that we keep the Sabbath holy. In other
words, we will go to church all day
long, service after service with no
interaction and think that we are
keeping the Sabbath. And even in this
training, I had to leave early because
it was a beautiful day and I wanted to
be in nature and walk and to take the
breath and and to Shabbat with my God. I
love my community. I love the people
that I was training, but at the end of
the day, this is a day that God set
apart for me.
And so why I say that is if I'm going to
present the Sabbath truth to someone, it
is not just trying to defend them with
scripture. It is not the the the gospel
doesn't need defending. What it needs is
an experience that you and I are having
that people can be drawn to the truth
that we have intellectually accepted but
not allowed our hearts to be transformed
by.
Come Shabbat with me. I'm gonna show you
why we have the best meals on Sabbath.
I'm gonna show you why nature is
literally the second hand of the
revelation of God's love for you and I.
Right? So, but the issue is that once we
try
to rearrange the way that we think or to
come to a point where it is not my duty
to try to convince this person that
they're wrong and I'm right, there has
to be a meekness and humility,
saints, daily that we are correcting our
faults and our
habits. And that takes true
humility. A true test of a Christian
isn't about how truthful I can be to the
world. And if I'm then persecuted for
the truth that I'm presenting, that's
not what brings forth
persecution. It is understand
this. I may I may not be able to
complete any more slides. I might have
to stay on this point. We have to
understand that Jesus who lived
perfectly, who was the embodiment of
meekness and humility, who literally
gave his life for
humanity. The reason why he was killed
and crucified is because his pure
character offended those who were not
humble and meek. They never daily
corrected their own faults. And so
because they see puress and meekness and
true godliness, it offended them and it
made them so uncomfortable and it
triggered them that it the only response
that came from the heart was to crucify
him. Right?
So, how many of
us truly are taking the time daily to
correct our faults? To say it wasn't
you, it was me. What you said wasn't
offensive. Is that I have a childhood
wound from my past that when I feel
threatened or I feel like somebody's not
accepting my opinion or whatever it may
be, I I get triggered and then I project
my insecurities onto you and I realize
it wasn't you, it was me. How many of us
have taken the time to actually do that
to anybody or most truthfully to
ourselves to say, "God, I come to you in
meekness and humility and I understand
that my ways of thinking and my patterns
of behavior is no one else's fault but
my own. It is not my mom's fault. It's
not my dad's fault. It's not my uh
ex-wife's fault or whoever it may be
that they made me who I am today." It's
true. They may have molded you in the
way that you think and the way that you
uh uh uh deal with difficult situations
in life and how you handle uh things as
a whole. But then God says now you've
entered into a relationship with me and
you can't worry about what people have
done to you. What about our relationship
and how are you growing in my
experience? But yeah, Gigi, you're
right. Sometimes we can't be right and
righteous.
It is truth and love as you mentioned,
right?
So I I I just wanted to share that
because I I'm I'm seeing a lot of it
regardless. It's not just about church,
it's about any debate, any topic. If
somebody disagree with with you, I I
want you to take the time to see how you
respond. And I want you to see, take the
time to see how your brothers and
sisters respond when when when when
clashes of ideas and ideologies and
worldviews come into
play. I'm just curious. And then are we
humble enough to say, "Lord, it was an
it was my pride, right, that got in the
way?" Because pride separates the soul
from
God. I had this discussion the other day
and and and we was talking about the
LGBT community and uh uh and and she was
like, "Well, is this a sin?" And and we
had this intense conversation and I
said, "You know what God hates the
most?" And I had to go show her the
Bible reference and I said, "What does
God call an
abomination? He says pride is an
abomination."
But we have thought that a group of
people who have a different lifestyle
than us are more sinful than we are when
God calls pride an abomination before
him. Yet we still possess pride in our
own hearts. And that is a thing that
separates us from God. But yet we can
judge other people for how they look
different, think different, and are
different. But yet we never correct our
daily habits and remove the pride that
is separating us from God.
I'm going to try to finish this quote.
It's a lengthy one. But let him that
that thinkketh he standeth take heed
lest he fall. Peace and rest will come
to you as you bring your will into
subjection to the will of Christ. So how
do we receive peace and rest saints?
When we submit to the will of God in our
lives for that day and how we respond in
that moment in whatever particular
situation, do we have trust? Do we have
faith or do we
not? Then the love of Christ once we
submit to the will, right? We then
receive the peace and and and rest that
God promises to that we will receive if
we comply to his plan. Then the love of
Christ will rule in the heart bringing
into captivity the savior notice this
the secret springs of action. God wants
to reveal to you his secrets. He wants
to to reveal to you his master plan not
only for your life but how you can be a
vessel to those you come in contact
every single day. Do people know who you
know in in in your personal relationship
with God at work and into your in your
interactions at church and and and and
family functions or wherever it is that
you're interacting with people on a
daily
basis. The h the hasty easily aroused
temper will be soothed and subdued by
the oil of Christ's grace. We're talking
about the Holy
Spirit. The oil of Christ's grace
soothes and subdues the very pride of
our lives. And if we submit that pride
to God and seek meekness and humility
and we find ourselves saying, God, I
want to follow. I want to be a man that
follows after your own heart.
The only way I can get there is if I
possess the spirit of God's in my
life. Notice this. The sense of sins
forgiven will bring that peace that
passes all
understanding. I'm going to conclude
here. It's 30 minutes. I know we got cut
short because of the technical
difficulties, but I want to leave it. I
want to leave it here. I want to leave
it here. We're going to pick this up
next week. We have to pick this up next
week,
right? I think too many of us think that
we are right when in reality we all
wrong. And just as that song articulated
beautifully,
God, don't give up on me
yet. Because the truth of the matter is,
there are things about myself that I'm
not even aware of. And I cannot base my
experiences on the past to think that it
will prepare me for today when today
will bring me new
challenges, new beasts, new new tests,
new
trials. I can't worry about tomorrow
because tomorrow is not promised. So
today as this person is commenting on my
Facebook post as I'm tweeting ideas and
thoughts as as I'm interacting and and
I'm seeing that people are not uh
accepting the messages that I'm sharing
or people have a differing thing of
opinion how am I responding am I showing
and revealing humility and meekness or
am I being triggered and am I projecting
the things that hurt me I want to make
sure that the other person hurts as
well.
There is there is danger when we think
that we are standing but God says don't
think that you are standing on your own
accord because you can easily
fall. Pride cometh before a
fall. So if we want to experience peace
and rest, we have to submit our will to
God's will for this day at this moment
in this situation in this trial in this
perplexity. Are you
following? And then as God as you submit
to God, then he whispers his plan of
action. Saints, that's beautiful. Like
he whispers the plan of action. Take a
deep breath. I know the tires blew out
on your
car, but I have a plan. And before you
get worked up and you start saying you
cursing out everybody in the tire shop
and and you kicking the car and you
forget about the reason why I blessed
you with this vehicle, I just need you
to take a deep breath. Control what you
can control. What is it that you can
control? Okay? Do I got AAA? Do I got
this? Do I have a phone call? And God is
going to guide you through the secret
springs of action that you need to take
at that moment as you surrender your
will in that moment to
God. That temper is soothed. Why?
Because I allow the Holy Spirit to work
in this
moment. The senses of things that I've
done in the past or in that moment where
I was at first angry and upset, God says
that's forgiven.
Initially, you reacted wrong, but you
allow the Holy Spirit, my Holy Spirit to
work in you and in this situation. And
now, don't worry about what just
happened. Here's peace that passes all
understanding. And that trial that
you're going through becomes a
testimony. That test becomes a
testimony. That trial now becomes a
stepping stone to the victory that God
says that you and I can have.
Saints, is that the experience that you
and I want to have with God? Because I
can testify that that's what he has done
with me. I'm still a work in process.
And just like Chandler Moore sung that
song, don't give up on me yet. I got new
scars. Just last week, I had to play
this song because I felt overwhelmed
with life. I had to I had to ask my
therapist. I was like, I might be going
through a midlife crisis. But there was
just a lot of burdens that I did not
surrender to God. But after having a
conversation and understanding, okay,
why is it that I'm uh barring in the
stresses of tomorrow when God only gave
me today? I can't worry about what
happened yesterday. What do I have? God
has blessed me with this. Let me use
what I got. And as soon as I started
complying to the plan of God, all of a
sudden, all my stresses have passed
away. All of a sudden, I got clarity of
vision. Everything started clicking.
Everything that God needed me to do, it
was getting done. Where it was a hold up
for the last month and a half, all of a
sudden everything just flowing. Why?
Because I took the time to say, "Okay,
God, I'm I'm doing it my way. I need you
to do it for me. What do I need to do?
How should I respond in this situation?"
He says, "You need to be honest with
yourself. You you're still dealing with
your insecurities. You're still dealing
with your abandonments. the these these
concept that you are leaning to those
vices, whatever it may be. You're
leaning onto it because you're entering
into a new space that you've never
entered into. And I need you to give
yourself grace, but I need you to trust
me in this area. Can you do that? I
trust you. I trust you. And I'll have
that honest conversation with the person
I needed to have that honest
conversation with and make men whoever I
need to make men. And all of a sudden,
that peace that passes all understanding
came into my mind. clarity of thought
and everything started falling into
place. Why? Because God started speaking
his secrets of springs of action to me.
Why? Because I submitted to his will. So
if it's your desire and Gigi, that's a
good question. Please post it in the um
in the mighty networks and I'm going to
respond to it by the end of this
weekend. By the end of this weekend.
That's a very good question. I like
those verses as well. But I want to
leave it here. How many of us is our
desire to say, "God, I I need to submit
and remove the pride from my heart. I
cannot do it on my own strength. I need
you to do it for me. And I come to you
with humility of heart and meekness. And
I ask that the Holy Spirit may do a work
in me that I cannot do it myself." If
that is your desire, ask that you may
put a one in the chat. And we're going
to conclude with a word of
prayer. We're going to conclude with a
word of prayer. And and I really want to
encourage as I'm waiting for the
responses via the chat, I I just need
one person to accept that. Amen.
Hallelujah. We got one. Um I really have
a passion for young people, y'all. I
really have a heart for this generation
that is behind
me because I realize that we have a very
unique position to reveal to them the
legacy that has been given to us and the
experiences that we've gone through and
the victories that we have
obtained. We can pass that down to be
honest and transparent about our
struggles that have led us to victories.
Notice I didn't just leave it as
struggles, but those struggles that have
led us to
victories. And so this is why I want to
create this safe place because many of
us are not even being honest of where
we're at. And as a result, we're losing
people because people know that they're
going through things, but they can't
identify with it because there's no one
else admitting that they are dealing
with the same
thing. So, praise God that I see um
those
requests. Yeah, brother Tennessee,
you're right. It's hard for young people
to hear about anything in regards to the
three angels message when us as a church
do not show
um true love to them. They can care less
about the three angels. You're right.
And the first angel declares the glory
of God, which is the literally the
character and the love of God. And yet
we have not experienced that in our own
lives. But we want to herald the third
angel and we want to talk about Babylon
falling and all of these empires. But
yet, we haven't even heeded to the first
command in Revelation 14 where it tells
us to fear God, to enter into a
relationship with him and to know who he
is truly. He is a God of love. That is
my email. If you have any questions, any
thoughts, any testimonies, please share
it there. And uh we're going to conclude
with a word of prayer. And I just want
to thank you uh so much guys. Um
Patrica, Patrice, what's good, girl? How
you doing? I see Indie inspire. I'm
going to see you alumni weekend. We'll
talk soon. But let us conclude with a
word of prayer. Invite the Holy Spirit
to seal the decision that we have made
tonight. Let us pray. Father, thank you
so much for your love, grace, and your
mercy. Thank you for the songs. Thank
you for the study. Thank you for the
reminder of why we need you
daily. Today, we need you. We need your
spirit today. We need your meekness and
humility. But Lord, in order for us to
experience the peace that passes all
understanding, in order for us to truly
be humble, in order for us to truly
experience weakness and to reveal your
character of love to those we come
across and to be honest with ourselves
is Lord, we need that pride to be
removed. We need to be corrected in the
areas where we realize that it's not
always about other people, but sometimes
it's us as well. We want to consent to
your plan today so that way we can live
out the greater picture and the greater
purpose that you have for us in our
lives. Thank you for the experience that
I had the last two weeks that had led me
to this point in time. I I thank you so
much for the songs that you have blessed
us with to re to to help us through the
difficult times and journeys that we
experience. And more importantly, I
thank you so much for the young people
and the people who are watching now who
has uh made a decision by putting one in
the chat and saying, "God, we need to
remove the pride from our lives. We need
to be honest and truthful with ourselves
and ask for meekness and humility." And
so, Lord, you will honor that request,
but we must first consent. And as a
result of consenting, then we'll find
the peace. Then you promise that you
will whisper us what we must do in those
very difficult trying moments. Thank you
so much for hearing but most importantly
answering our prayer for we ask this in
Jesus precious and holy name. Amen and
amen. We will see you guys next week
Thursday. I know there will be a pause
for one week as uh we will be
celebrating alumni weekend um for my
alma mater Oakwood University. I believe
it's next week. If it's not next week,
it's the following week, but we'll give
an update. Please, by all means, um,
follow us on Mighty Networks. You can
follow me on social media, Instagram, as
well as, uh, Facebook. It is Lwami
Richardson. If you just type that into
the search bar, my name should pop up.
But there's my email address. If you
guys have any questions, please do not
hesitate to reach out. Until next week,
may God bless. Peace.